MALICK BA

Arlington, VA 22201 (202) 552-9908 | malickbax@gmail.com

Portfolio: malickbax.github.io/portfolio

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/malickbax | GitHub: github.com/malickbax

Front End Software Engineer with working knowledge of the Back End and solid experience in project management, leveraging background in International Security to provide unique perspectives on Agile Software Development and how end-users interact with websites. George Washington University-Certified Full Stack Web Developer. Dedicated teamwork enthusiast. Native fluency in French.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Vue.js, Node.js, SQL

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING EXPERIENCE

Employee Teams Generator

github.com/malickbax/employee-teams-generator | Walkthrough video available here

- Summary: Backend application built to generate profiles based on inputs from Node.js Inquirer
 Module. The information entered by the user is displayed on a generated HTML file. The
 application demonstrates the capabilities of Jest and Object Oriented Programming (OOP) when
 building everyday-use applications.
- Role: Back End Developer
- Technologies: Node.js, JavaScript, NPM, Object Oriented Programming

Work Day Planner

github.com/malickbax/workday-planner |malickbax.github.io/workday-planner

- Summary: A simple calendar application that allows users to save events for each hour of the day.
 This app runs in the browser and features dynamically updated HTML and CSS powered by jQuery.
- Role: Front and Back End Engineer
- Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, iQuery

Bragging Rights Web Application

github.com/malickbax/bragging-rights | aqueous-stream-06315.herokuapp.com

- **Summary:** Blog-style web platform that allows users to post game achievements and view their fellow users achievements.
- Role: Front End Developer
- Technologies: Node.js, Express.JS, MySQL, Sequelize, Bootstrap, Upload.JS, Dotenv, Bcrypt

Run Buddy

github.com/malickbax/run-buddy | malickbax.github.io/run-buddy

- **Summary:** An e-commerce type of website that offers fitness training services. Website front-end layout if fully adjustable to all computer and mobile screen sizes.
- Role: Front End Developer
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Program Officer, Team Lead

Strategic Capacity Group

June 2019 - Present

McLean, VA

- Initiated and led the training of 13 new Project Coordinators and conceptualized training manuals improving the overall human resource and project deliverables to State Department's INL by 20%
- Spearheaded the logistics efforts during deployment of American, Canadian and French law enforcement trainers globally. Led all aspects of logistics support for 90+ events per year drawing an attendance of more than 1,000 partners, resulting in a 93% partner satisfaction
- Built relationships with 40+ stakeholders per year while prioritizing, negotiating, and working with a
 variety of partners to address the logistics of event planning and execution in various countries

Freelance Web Content Developer

Sept 2016 - June 2019

Freelance

London, UK

- Developed and implemented effective Search Engine Optimization (SEO) strategies to maximize search rankings, user engagement and online sales
- Coordinated content, design, social media, pay-per-click (PPC) marketing and other activities.
 Maintained internet sites and social media pages as they grew to 2,000+ followers and images that generated 400 hits daily, resulting in a better user engagement. Praised for the ability to solve difficult problems independently and efficiently
- Initiated and led customer outreach and communication efforts, leading to a 20% increase in weekly traffic in online activity. Developed engaging content that aligns with brand strategy, and addressed needs of stakeholders and clients

Transnational Threats Research Intern

August 2015 - May 2016

Center for Strategic and International Studies

Washington, DC

- Achieved 120+ daily Open Source Intelligence (OSINT) research operations on violent extremist
 organizations and counterterrorism strategies in various areas, including the United States,
 Western Europe, the African continent, the Middle-East and Asia
- Provided presentations in English and French to leadership ahead of meetings with members of U.S. law enforcement and intelligence community, leading to successful delivery of research findings within deadlines
- Used editorial skills in a team environment to develop and manage editorial calendar, collaborated with the media department for work on written products to be published. Broadened and maintained an extensive network of contacts and was commended for attention to detail and accuracy

EDUCATION

Certificate - Full Stack Web Development

George Washington University

2022

Washington, DC

Master of Science - International Relations

London School of Economics (LSE)

2017 London, UK

Bachelor of Arts - Political Science

2015

University of Missouri

Kansas City, MO